Let's walk through an example of a factor to learn more about what a factor looks like.
我们将通过一个因子示例讲解因子是什么样的
We'll look at a momentum factor.
我们将以一个动量因子为例
So, let's say we have a hypothesis that the one year return of
假设股票的过去一年的年华收益率
a stock gives some signal about future returns over the next few days.
可以帮助预测未来几天的收益率
To create a factor,
为了创建因子
we get price data for stocks within the stock universe of interests and
我们获取股票池中股票的股价数据
calculate the percent change of today's price from the price from one year ago.
并计算今天的股价对比一年前的股价的百分比变化是多少
We repeat this for several days of data.
对若干天的数据重复这一过程
The collection of one year returns for the set of stocks
对一组股票一年收益率集合
over time is what we'll refer to as a factor.
称为因子
It represents information that can potentially be useful in deciding how much weight
因子包含的信息有助于我们判断
we'll give each stock in the portfolio and whether to long or short each stock.
为投资组合中的每支股票分配多少权重以及是否做多或做空每支股票
Now, the question is how do we use this factor?
现在的问题是如何利用这些因子？
Do we use it to try and predict how much a stock will go up the next day?
我们利用因子预测股票第二天将上涨多少吗？
That's quite difficult when dealing with data that has a lot of noise.
当数据有很多噪点时 这种预测很困难
What we actually want to do is to use the factor value for
我们实际上希望根据因子值
each stock to compare it to
将每支股票
other stocks that are candidates to be included in a portfolio.
与可能要添加到投资组合中的其他候选股票进行比较
So, let's say we have a portfolio of just two stocks, Apple and NVIDIA.
假设某个投资组合中只有两支股票 Apple 和 NVIDIA
On August 3rd, 2018,
在 2018 年 8 月 3 日
Apple's stock price reached $208 per share valuing the company at $1 trillion.
Apple 的股价达到 208 美元/股 公司市值为 1 万亿美元
Its price one year before was $156.
一年前的股价是 156 美元
So, Apple's one year return was about 33 percent.
所以 Apple 这一年的收益率约为 33%
NVIDIA stock price on August 3rd,
在 2018 年 8 月 3 日
2018 was $252, valuing the company at $152 billion.
NVIDIA 的股价是 252 美元 公司市值为 1520 亿美元
NVIDIA's price one year before was $166 per share.
NVIDIA 一年前的股价是 166 美元
So, its annual return was about 52 percent.
它这一年的收益率约为 52%
To summarize, Apple's factor value is
总结下 对于这一天来说
0.33 and NVIDIA's factor value is 0.52 for this one day.
Apple 的因子值为 0.33 NVIDIA 的因子值为 0.52
Now, what? Well, since the hypothesis of
接下来呢？我们的因子假设是
our factor is that a higher number indicates higher future returns,
因子越大 表明未来收益率越高
then according to our factor and its associated hypothesis,
根据我们的因子和相关假设
NVIDIA's return may be higher relative to Apple's over the next few days.
在接下来的几天内 NVIDIA 的收益率可能比 Apple 高
One way to act on this signal is to put more money on the stock for which the factor has
对这种信号采取措施的一种方式是
a more positive value and less money on the stock that has a less positive value.
对因子为更高正数的股票投入更多资金并对因子为更低正数的股票投入更少的资金
We could also short a stock that has a negative factor value.
我们还可以对因子为负数的股票做空
In this hypothetical example,
在这个假设示例中
we want to give a higher positive weight to NVIDIA relative to Apple.
我们希望对 NVIDIA 分配的正权重比 Apple 的高